Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. David Baker papers, 1980-1998 and undated RL.11463
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. David Baker papers
1980-1998 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11463
4.0 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. The London Office first opened in 1899. David Baker was an executive with JWT London and JWT Europe 1968-2001. Collection includes correspondence, market research reports, advertising campaign planning and strategy documents, print advertisements and other printed materials. Companies represented include Elizabeth Arden, Heineken, J&B Scotch, Jaguar, Kraft, Scott Paper, Unilever and Warner-Lambert. Materials in English, German and Spanish. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: General Files; Account Files.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. The London Office first opened in 1899. David Baker was an executive with JWT London and JWT Europe 1968-2001. Reading University 1968 (Mathematics); JWT London: Media Department Trainee 1968; Account Planning 1970; Associate Director 1975; Account Representative(Persil) 1976; Director in Charge of Accounts 1980; Head of Planning, JWT Europe, Worldwide Director for Thompson Total Branding 1997; retired 2001.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. David Baker papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2008.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office records; J. Walter Thompson Company. Account files; J. Walter Thompson Company. International Offices records; J. Walter Thompson Company. Thompson Way/Thompson Total Branding records
Collection Overview
Includes correspondence, market research reports, advertising campaign planning and strategy documents, print advertisements and other printed materials. Companies represented include Elizabeth Arden, Heineken, J&B Scotch, Jaguar, Kraft, Scott Paper, Unilever and Warner-Lambert. Materials in English, German and Spanish. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising executives -- England; Advertising; Advertising agencies -- Great Britain; Advertising agencies -- Great Britain -- History; Advertising executives -- Great Britain; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Elizabeth Arden, Inc.; Heineken's BierBouwerij Maatschappij; Kraft Foods Company; Scott Paper Company; Unilever (Firm); Warner-Lambert Company
- General Files, 1980-1996 and undated; 1
  - Advertising research, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Asia Pacific planning file, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Between a Rock and a Hard Place, 1993 (Box 1)
  - BMW, Mercedes ads (in German), 1993 (Box 1)
  - Brand Architects (slide presentation), undated (Box 1)
  - Brand Building, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Brand strategies, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Branding articles (English and German), 1994 (Box 1)
  - Brands as Services, undated (Box 1)
  - Chesebrough-Pond's Advertising Course (CPAP), undated (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Death of Added Value, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Henley Centre research reports, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
  - How Long Has This Been Going On? Transnational Advertising: A Flexible View, undated (Box 1)
  - Integrated Communications, undated (Box 1)
  - Integrated Marketing Communications, 1991-1992; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - International Brand Equity Management, 1995 (Box 1)
  - ISL Marketing, undated (Box 2)
  - JWT Chicago: Day One, 1992 (Box 2)
  - JWT Consumer Insight Training, 1993 (Box 2)
  - JWT Group Annual Report, 1984 (Box 2)
  - JWT List of Accounts, 1985 (Box 2)
  - JWT National Creative Awards, 1980-1985 (Box 2)
  - JWT Strategy, undated (Box 2)
  - JWT Worldwide Brand Audit, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Leading Change: Why Transformation Efforts Fail (John Kotter), 1995 (Box 2)
  - Manor Bakeries Workshop, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Market Modeling: An Introduction, undated (Box 2)
  - Market Sector: Food--Whisky, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Marketing Target Group, undated (Box 2)
  - "Old Reliable" JWT New York Is Now a "Hot" Creative Shop, 1984 (Box 2)
  - The Planning Cycle, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Planning in the European Context, undated (Box 2)
  - Presentation Bank, 1993-1994 (Box 2)
  - Pricing for Profit, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Recruitment Goes Critical, undated (Box 2)
  - Relevant material from David Clifford, undated (Box 2)
  - Revitalizing Mature Brands, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Strategies: Who Needs 'Em?, undated (Box 3)
  - Thompson Total Branding, 1994-1995 (Box 3)
  - Thompson Way, 1989 and undated; 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Thompson Way, undated (Box 8)
  - Training, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
  - Why Account Planning?, 1995 (Box 3)
  - WPP Atticus Awards, 1993-1996; 6 folders (Box 3)
- Account Files, 1984-1998 and undated; 2
  - Babies R Us (Spanish), 1997 (Box 4)
  - Belling & Co., 1990-1994 (Box 4)
  - Black and Decker, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Diageo, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Elida Gibbs--Mentadent, 1993-1994 (Box 4)
  - Elizabeth Arden, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Elizabeth Arden--5th Avenue, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Elizabeth Arden--Strategy meeting, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Elizabeth Arden--What Women Want, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Heineken, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Heineken--Amstel, 1994 (Box 4)
  - Heineken--Brand Dynamics, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Heineken--Communication Strategy, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Heineken--Myth Project, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Heineken--Presentation, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Heineken--Strategic Planning, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Heineken--Strategic Planning, 1995 (Box 5)
  - J&B--Information Dossier, 1996 (Box 5)
  - J&B--J&B in Portugal, 1997 (Box 5)
  - J&B--JWT Briefing, undated (Box 5)
  - J&B--Questions and Answers: Scotch Whisky, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Jaguar, 1993-1994 (Box 8)
  - Jaguar--Blueprint for Brand Renewal and Growth (Ogilvy & Mather), 1993 (Box 5)
  - Jaguar--Creative, undated (Box 5)
  - Jaguar--X300 Communications Strategy Development, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Jaguar--X300 Planning, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Jaguar--X300/XJ launch, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Kellogg's, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Kellogg's--European Planning, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Kraft Jacobs Suchard, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Kraft Jacobs Suchard--Grill + Gull creative strategy document (German), 1996 (Box 5)
  - Kraft Jacobs Suchard--Uses and Abuses of Research, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Nestle, 1993-1995 (Box 6)
  - Scott Paper, 1994 (Box 6)
  - Scott Paper--Andrex, 1994 (Box 6)
  - Scott Paper--Andrex Moist Tissues, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Scott Paper--Andrex report, 1994 (Box 6)
  - Scott Paper--Andrex/Scottex, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Scott Paper--Andrex--Sold on a Pup, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Scott Paper--European Management Review, 1995 (Box 6)
  - Scott Paper--JWT Advertising Meeting, 1995 (Box 6)
  - Scott Paper--Scottex, 1994-1996; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Scott Paper--Scottex/Andrex Creative Brief Summary, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Scott Paper--Worldwide Scott Management Meeting, 1994 (Box 6)
  - TNT Mailfast, 1994-1995; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - TNT Mailfast--Market Potential for a New European Parcel Service, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Unilever, 1995-1996 (Box 7)
  - Unilever--Food Industry Facing 1994-2004 (Box 7)
  - Unilever--Good Advertising Practice, undated (Box 7)
  - Unilever--New Worldwide Brand Development, 1996 (Box 7)
  - Unilever--Oxo, 1995 (Box 7)
  - Unilever--Plan for Great Advertisingk, undated (Box 7)
  - Unilever--Sponsorship: A Valuable Brand Marketing Tool, 1994-1995; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Warner-Lambert, 1994-1995 (Box 7)
  - Warner-Lambert--Clorets, 1995 (Box 7)
  - Warner-Lambert--Trident, 1994 (Box 7)